housewares.org 2002-12-05

# Privacy Policy - housewares.org

Home > Privacy Policy   

* * *

### Privacy Policy

**Housewares.org Privacy Policy**  
housewares.org has created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to your privacy. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for this website: housewares.org.

**Information That We Collect and How We Use It**

When you register for the site or sign up for membership, we may collect name, address, and email address, unique identifiers such as your user ID and password, your credit card number, and some demographic information (zip code, age, income level).

When you order a product or service, we may collect name, mailing address, email address, and credit card number. This allows us to notify you of your order status, to address any issues with your order, and to process and fulfill your order. 

When you sign up for an information service (such as a newsletter or vendor information) or other site announcements, we need an e-mail address, which we use to send the information you've requested. 

When you enter a contest or other promotional feature, we may ask for your name, address and e-mail address so we can administer the contest and notify winners. 

At various times, we may ask you to volunteer other information about your interests, preferences, etc. Your input is used to help us make the information we provide you more relevant and useful. 

We personalize your experience by presenting offers that might be of interest and by presenting content that best matches your interests. We also monitor site traffic patterns and site usage to help us develop the design and layout of the site. 

We may also use the information we collect to occasionally notify you about important functionality changes to the Web site, new services and special offers we think you'll find valuable. This will only occur if you have requested such information; you always have the option of opting-out from being contacted from future mailings; see the choice/opt-out section below.

In general, all the information that you provide is used to tailor your experience at our site, showing you offers that we think you might be interested in, and displaying content according to your preferences. This information is shared with partners on an aggregate basis so that we can provide the most relevant offers. 

**How We Protect Your Information**

When you place orders or access your account information, we use a secure server. The secure server software (SSL) encrypts all information you input before it is sent to us. Furthermore, all of the customer data we collect is protected against unauthorized access. 

**The Benefit of Cookies**

"Cookies" are small pieces of information that are stored by your browser on your computer's hard drive. Cookies contain data to help us provide a personalized site experience and to show you offers that may be of interest. Our cookies do not contain any personally identifying information.

Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually change your browser to prevent that. Even without a cookie, you can still use most of the features in our store, including placing items in a shopping cart and purchasing them.

We use a third-party service to display ads on our site; these ads may contain cookies and we do not have access to this information. Our partner may also combine the non-personally-identifiable data from this cookie with login and demographic data that we may provide in order to more precisely target offers.

**Public Forums**

This site makes chat rooms, forums, message boards, and/or news groups available to its users. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information. 

**Security**

This site has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. 

**No Disclosure to Outside Parties**

We do not sell, trade, or rent your personal information to others. We may provide aggregate statistics about our customers, sales, traffic patterns, and related site information to reputable third-party vendors, but these statistics will include no personally identifying or contact information. We may release account information when we believe, in good faith, that such release is reasonably necessary to (i) comply with law, (ii) enforce or apply the terms of any of our user agreements or (iii) protect the rights, property or safety of the sponsoring association, eSociety, our users or others.

**Sites That We Link To**

This site contains links to other web sites. Housewares.org is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such web sites. Although some of the sites that we link to may know that you came from housewares.org, we do not provide any other information about you to our partners.

**Choice/Opt-Out**

Our site will provide the opportunity to opt-out of receiving future communications from us and our partners when you register for the site or for an event, sign up for special offers or promotions, purchase an item, request information, fill out a survey, or join the association.

At any time, you can choose to opt-out of receiving future communications on the Account Update page on this site. 

**Correct/Update**

At any time, you can change your information on the Account Update page on this site. 

**In Summary**

We are committed to protecting your privacy. We use the information we collect on the site to make shopping on the site possible and to enhance your overall site experience. We do not sell, trade, or rent your personal information to others.

**Your Consent**

By using our Web site, you consent to the collection and use of this information. If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page so that you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. 

**Contacting the Web Site**

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this site, you can contact: [admin@housewares.org](mailto:admin@housewares.org)

March 2000
